A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Office of the Vice President, Office Files of Francis X. Sutton FA568
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Budget Files, 1966-1983; IV
  - Overseas Development -- Completed Grants and Projects (1951-1967) (2 of 2), circa 1967 (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - Overseas Development -- Interim Report No.34 -- Appropriations Summaries, 1966 December 31 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Overseas Development -- Interim Report No.35, 36, 37 -- Appropriations Summaries, 1967 March-December (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Overseas Development -- Standard Report No.40 -- Appropriations Summaries, Status of Active Grants and Projects (1 of 2), 1967 September 30 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Overseas Development -- Standard Report No.40 -- Appropriations Summaries, Status of Active Grants and Projects (2 of 2), 1967 September 30 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Planning Agenda -- Memoranda Re: Cost Actions, Budget Planning for FY 1970-1975, Information Papers (folder 1 of 3), 1969-1972 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Planning Agenda -- Memoranda Re: Cost Actions, Budget Planning for FY 1970-1975, Information Papers (folder 2 of 3), 1972 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Planning Agenda -- Memoranda Re: Cost Actions, Budget Planning for FY 1970-1975, Information Papers (folder 3 of 3), 1972-1973 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Program Actions -- Budgets and Memoranda Re: Proposed Grant Actions (folder 1 of 5), 1979 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Program Actions (folder 2 of 5), 1979-1980 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Program Actions (folder 3 of 5), 1980 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Program Actions (folder 4 of 5), 1980-1981 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Program Actions (folder 5 of 5), 1981 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Program Management Costs -- Memoranda and Grant Recommendations/Cost Actions (folder 1 of 7), 1968-1970 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Program Management Costs -- Memoranda and Grant Recommendations/Cost Actions (folder 2 of 7), 1971-1972 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Program Management Costs -- Memoranda and Grant Recommendations/Cost Actions (folder 3 of 7), 1973 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Program Management Costs -- Memoranda and Grant Recommendations/Cost Actions (folder 4 of 7), 1974 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Program Management Costs -- Memoranda and Grant Recommendations/Cost actions (folder 5 of 7), 1975 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Program Management Costs -- Memoranda and Grant Recommendations/Cost Actions (folder 6 of 7), 1977 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Program Management Costs -- Memoranda and Grant Recommendations/Cost Actions (folder 7 of 7), 1978-1979 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Proposed Budget for Fiscal Years 1984-1985, 1983 June (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Quarterly Reports -- Summaries of Grants and Projects, 1968-1971 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Statement of Appropriations (Oct 1966-Jan 31, 1967) (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Tie-Off Appropriations -- Memoranda, Docket Item and Budget Information, 1975-1980 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Year-End Balances -- Memoranda and Notes, 1971-1980 (Box 56, Folder 8)
- Speeches and Articles, 1961-1989; V
  Dr. Sutton regularly presented and published his opinions on and the results of his Ford Foundation work. His speeches, lectures, and articles are arranged chronologically from 1961 through 1982. Speeches and lectures Dr. Sutton gave to university audiences, conference attendees, government employees and Foundation colleagues make up the bulk of the series. Also included are articles written by Dr. Sutton for print in non-Ford Foundation publications, including journals, magazines, and newspapers.
  - Address to Plenary Session of UNESCO Conference on Higher Education in Africa, Addis Ababa, 1961 May 23 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - "Education in Changing Africa" -- Address at 8th National Conference of the US National Commission for UNESCO, Boston, MA, 1961 October 22-26 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - "Africa Today" -- Lecture at Cornell University, 1961 November 2 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - "The Problem of Fitness for Self Government" -- Lecture at Swathmore College, Feb 11, 1962, revised Feb 1964 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - "Developing the Idea of a New Social Science Encyclopedia" -- American Behavioral Scientist (reprint), 1962 September (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - "Fitness for Self-Government and Development in Modern Africa" -- 5th World Conference of Sociology, Washington, DC, 1962 September (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - "Africa's Educational Needs and Opportunities" -- Man and Africa Conference, Addis Ababa, 1964 October 1-6 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - "Technical Assistance" -- Prepared for the International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1965 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - "Observations on the Situations in East and Central Africa", 1965 April (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Operation Janus -- 4 volumes, circa 1966 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - "Aid and the Problems of Education, Employment and Rural Development" -- Conference on Education, Employment and Rural Development, University College Nairobi, 1966 September 22 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - "Tolerable Rates of Economic Development and Social Change" -- African Social Research, 1966 December 2 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - "The Importance of Higher Education to Development" -- Higher Education and the International Flow of Manpower: Implications for the Developing World, 1967 (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - "American Foundations and U.S. Public Diplomacy" -- Symposium on Future of U.S. Public Diplomacy, 1968 July 22 (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - "The Future of Technical Assistance in Professional Cooperation" -- Presidential Task Force on International Cooperation, 1969 December 31 (Box 57, Folder 15)
  - "The Ford Foundation and Development in Tanzania" -- OECO Seminar on Foreign Aid and Rural Development, University College, Dar es Salaam, 1970 January 19-23 (Box 57, Folder 16)
  - "African Universities and the Process of Change in Middle Africa" -- Conference on the Tasks of Universities in a Changing World, University of Notre Dame, South Bend, IN, 1970 February 26 (Box 57, Folder 17)
  - "Cultural Implications of Aid Programs" -- Harry S. Truman Research Institute of the Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Publication #6 (reprint), 1970 May (Box 57, Folder 18)
  - "Research, Scholarship and Cultural Development" -- Education Session, International Division Conference, New Delhi, India, 1971 October 25-29 (Box 57, Folder 19)
  - "Beginnings of the Foundation's Program in North Africa" -- Ford Foundation Review Conference on the Middle East and North Africa, 1972 June (Box 57, Folder 20)
  - "A Novitiate in Eastern Europe", 1973 April 24-May 5 (Box 57, Folder 21)
  - "Black Africa in 1973: The Search for Equality in an Unequal World" -- Council on Foreign Relations Discussion Group on African Development, 1973 May 10 (Box 57, Folder 22)
  - "Public Management and Development Assistance" -- Maxwell School, Syracuse University, 1974 April 18 (Box 57, Folder 23)
  - "Meeting on the Social Sciences in the Middle East" -- Alexandria, Egypt, 1974 July 1-8 (Box 57, Folder 24)
  - "International Studies in Our Future International Programs", 1974 July 17 (Box 57, Folder 25)
  - "Remarks on the Climate for Funding from Foundations" -- Conference on Funding for International Education, Columbia University, NYC, 1975 February 13-14 (Box 57, Folder 26)
  - "The Ford Foundation and African Studies" -- A Quarterly Journal of Opinion (reprint), 1976 (Box 57, Folder 27)
  - "The Foundations and the Governments of Developing Countries" -- Annual Meeting of the American Political Science Association, Chicago, IL, 1976 September 2-5 (Box 57, Folder 28)
  - "Comments on International Education for the Sub-Committee on International Operations, US House of Representatives", 1978 August 29 (Box 57, Folder 29)
  - "The Public Purposes of Private Colleges" -- Panel Discussion at Sarah Lawrence College, 1981 November 6 (Box 57, Folder 30)
  - "The Funding of International Cooperation in Higher Education Scholarship and Research" -- University of Hawaii, 1982 April 29 (Box 57, Folder 31)
  - "Rationality, Development and Scholarship" -- 1st Annual Assembly of ACLS-SSRC Joint Area Committees, 1982 October 39 (Box 57, Folder 32)
  - "The Role of Foundations in Development" -- The President's World University Series No. 1, Texas A&M University, 1982 December (Box 57, Folder 33)
  - "Building Capability for Policy Analysis" by Samuel Paul, David Steedman and Francis Sutton, 1989 July
- Ford Foundation History Project, Regional Files, 1951-1985; VI
  The files within this series consist of Dr. Sutton's research notes and materials on the history of the Ford Foundation's international activities and were amassed during his post-retirement consultancy. Comprised of memoranda, reports, meeting and conference materials, trip files, and notes, the History Project Regional Files detail the Foundation's international interests and provide a framework for understanding its grant-making agenda in each region.
  Arranged alphabetically by region.
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Bangladesh -- Grant and Budget Lists, 1946-1982, 1981-1982 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Burma -- Inventories/Box Listings of Reports and Office Files Regarding Burma in Ford Foundation Archives, 1983 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Burma -- Memoranda Re: Burmese Development Planning, 1955-1956 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Burma -- Notes Re: Foundation Work in Burma, 1981-1983 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Burma -- Report, "Recommendations on Evaluation of MEC Program" by Ronald Jones, 1953 September 16 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Burma -- Report, "Informational Meeting with John Everton", 1953 December 3 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Burma -- Reports Re: Ford Foundation in Burma, 1953-1955 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Burma -- Report, "Report on Education in Burma", 1956 July 18 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Burma -- Report, "Historical Summary of the Ford Foundation Program in Burma, 1953-1962", 1965 May (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Burma -- Report, "Burma Revisited: 19 Years Later" by William K. Gamble, 1971 November 29 (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Burma -- Report, "More Than You Ever Wanted to Know About Burma and Were Too Wise to Ask" by David Finkelstein, 1975 November 21 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- China -- Grants -- Recommendations for Grant Action and Summary of Foundation Activities, 1979-1984 (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- China -- Notes and Response to Washington Post Column Re: Ford Foundation Grant for U.S.-China Relations, 1967 (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- China -- Reports Re: Foundation Work and Interests in China, 1971-1983 (Box 58, Folder 14)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Grant Listings (South and Southeast Asia), 1981 (Box 58, Folder 15)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Country Visit (October 1968) -- Correspondence, Itinerary, Report, 1968 May-December (Box 58, Folder 16)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Country Visit (October 1978) -- Itinerary, 1978 September (Box 58, Folder 17)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Country Visit (Feb-Mar 1985) -- Correspondence, Pre-trip Planning Materials, 1985 January-February (Box 58, Folder 18)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Ford Foundation Booklets/Publications Re: Foundation Work in India, 1961-1968 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Meeting -- Family Planning/Population Programme (Sep 1969) -- Agendas, Memoranda, Meeting Materials (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Meeting (Apr 14, 1976) -- Agenda, Participants List, Notes, 1976 April 14 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Memoranda Re: Ford Foundation in India (main correspondents: F.F. Hill and F.C. Ward) (folder 1 of 2), 1951-1957 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Memoranda Re: Ford Foundation in India (folder 2 of 2), 1967-1985 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Memoranda Re: Program Budgets for FY 1980-1981, 1979-1980 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Memoranda Re: Goldsmith Report, "Foreign Aid and Agricultural Development in India", 1984-1985 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Notes, Observations Re: Visits to India, 1977-1984 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Notes, Reflections on India by Douglas Ensminger, 1985-1986 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Notes, Research Materials Re: Foundation Work in India, circa 1985 (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Reports, Program Updates Re: Foundation Work in India, 1952-1959, 1982 (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Report, "The Social Sciences in India: A Preliminary View" by John Bresnan, 1968 April 25 (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Report, "History of the Foundation in India", 1978 June (Box 59, Folder 13)
    General
    File is empty. The report was moved to Ford Foundation 'Cataloged Reports' #019666.
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Report, "The Role of a Private Foreign Philanthropy in India" by Lincoln C. Chen, 1984 September 14 (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Report, "The International Philanthropic Foundations and Developing Countries" by Jagat Mehta, 1985 April 9 (Box 59, Folder 15)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Report, "A Brief Note on the Ford Foundation's Current Program in India" With Photo (separated, see: Visual Materials), 1985 September 19 (Box 59, Folder 16)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India -- Report, "Ford Philanthropy and Indian Education" by Neelu Sancheti, undated (Box 59, Folder 17)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India and Nepal -- Bibliography of Ford Foundation Papers on India and Nepal, 1967 October (Box 59, Folder 18)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India and Pakistan -- Memoranda Re: Early Work and Foundation Grants, 1951 October-December (Box 59, Folder 19)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India and Pakistan -- Manuscript, Correspondence, Notes Re: "Western Intellectuals and South Asia: The Ford Foundation and Western Economists in India and Pakistan, 1950-1970" by George Rosen (folder 1 of 2), 1982-1983 (Box 59, Folder 20)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India and Pakistan -- Manuscript, "Western Intellectuals and South Asia: The Ford Foundation and Western Economists in India and Pakistan, 1950-1970" by George Rosen (folder 2 of 2), 1983 (Box 59, Folder 21)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- India and Pakistan -- Report, "Report on Visit to Near East, South Asia and Far East" and Report Summary by Paul Hoffman, 1951, 1984 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Indonesia -- Grant Listings and Funding Reports, 1980-1981 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Indonesia -- Notes, Program Staff List, undated (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Indonesia and Burma -- Report, "Indonesia and Burma" by Edwin G. Arnold and Dyke Brown, 1952 September 21 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Indonesia -- Report, "Population and Family Planning in Indonesia" by Gordon W. Perkin, 1968 October (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Indonesia -- Reports Re: Foundation Work in Indonesia and Indonesian Government, 1969 September (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Indonesia -- Report, "Indonesia's Sociolingustic Situation" by John M. Echols, circa 1970 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Indonesia -- Reports -- Ford Foundation Annual Reports on Indonesian Activities, 1970-1972 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Meeting Files -- Social Science and Management Research on Population (10/1/71) -- Agendas, Discussion Papers, Notes (folder 1 of 2), 1970-1971 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Meeting Files -- Social Science and Management Research on Population (10/1/71) -- Discussion Papers (folder 2 of 2), 1971 May-June (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Memorandum, "Notes on a Trip Across Asia" by Don K Price, 1955 January 19 (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Memoranda Re: Arts in Asia and Cultural Programming, 1968 (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Memoranda, Reports, Grant Summaries Re: Foundation Work in Asia, FY 1968-1970, 1969-1971 (Box 60, Folder 13)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Nepal -- Memoranda, Correspondence, Notes, Grant Requests, Expenditure Reports Re: Foundation Work in Nepal, 1952-1985 (Box 60, Folder 14)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Pakistan -- Ford Foundation Booklets/Publications Re: Work in Pakistan, 1959 May (Box 60, Folder 15)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Pakistan -- Meeting Files -- Beirut Meetings (Apr 21-22, 1971) -- Suggested Agenda and Meeting Materials, 1970 December-1971 April (Box 60, Folder 16)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Pakistan -- Memoranda Re: Beirut Meetings on Pakistan and Foundation Work in Pakistan, 1971 March-June (Box 60, Folder 17)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Pakistan -- Memoranda, Reports Re: Foundation Work in Pakistan and Pakistan Review, 1969-1971 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Pakistan -- Memoranda Re: 1979 Riots in Pakistan, Burning of U.S. Embassy, Office Closing, 1979-1981 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Pakistan -- Public Management Review, 1973 September (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Pakistan -- U.S. Overseas Loans and Grants to Pakistan, 1946-1982, circa 1982 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Report, "Asian Population Review: A Tentative Frame of Reference" by Samuel Bunker, 1972 March 31 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Report, "An Asian Regional Program in Archaeology, Conservation and Museology" by Lisa Lyons, 1977 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Report, "The Ford Foundation and Asia" by John Bresnall, 1979 October (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Report, "Report to the Ford Foundation on International Economics Programs in South East Asia" by Ronald Findlay, 1983 August (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Asia and the Pacific -- Report, "The Ford Foundation and Asia" for Board of Trustees Meeting, 1983 September 28 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Europe -- Correspondence, Board of Trustees Meeting Program Docket (1958), Article Re: Artists in Residence and Free University of Berlin Foundation Programs, 1958-1964 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Europe -- Grant Recommendation Re: European Security Study, 1983 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Europe -- Notes, Reference Materials Re: Eastern Europe, Poland and Foundation Work, 1983-1984 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Europe -- Program Docket for Board of Trustees Meeting (Dec 7, 1956) -- "Program for Europe" (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Europe -- Report, "The Foundation's Activities in Europe", 1968 March (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Europe -- Report, "Europe and the United States in a Changing World", 1973 March (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - Europe -- Report, "A Novitiate in Eastern Europe" by Francis X. Sutton, 1973 July (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - Europe -- Report, "Memorandum on East European Emigre Publishing in the Field of Human Rights" by Michael Scammell and Leonard Shatzkin, 1983 October 11 (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - Latin America and the Caribbean -- General -- Notes, Grant Information, circa 1984-1985 (Box 61, Folder 18)
  - Latin America and the Caribbean -- Memoranda Re: Grant Evaluations, 1960-1967 (Box 61, Folder 19)
  - Latin America and the Caribbean -- Report, "The Development of the Social Sciences in Latin America" by Reynold E. Carlson, 1965 November (Box 61, Folder 20)
  - Latin America and the Caribbean -- Report, "The Ford Foundation's Activities in Latin America and the Caribbean", 1967 September (Box 61, Folder 21)
  - Latin America and the Caribbean -- Report, Ford Foundation in Mexico and Central America, 1969 February (Box 61, Folder 22)
  - Latin America and the Caribbean -- Report, "The Foundation's Latin America and the Caribbean Program: A Review and a Look Ahead", 1972 March 5 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Latin America and the Caribbean -- Report, Ford Foundation Program in Peru, 1974 December (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Latin America and the Caribbean -- Report, "The Ford Foundation's Latin America and the Caribbean Program" (separated), 1984 March 28 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Latin America and the Caribbean -- Resources for the Future Grant Evaluation, 1984 December 26 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Latin America and the Caribbean -- University of the West Indies Grant Proposal, 1984 February (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Africa Program Review (Dec 1970) -- Reports, Discussion Papers, Grant Statistics (folder 1 of 7), 1969-1970 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Africa Program Review (Dec 1970) -- Reports, Discussion Papers (folder 2 of 7) (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Africa Program Review (Dec 1970) -- Reports, Discussion Papers (folder 3 of 7) (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Africa Program Review (Dec 1970) -- Reports, Discussion Papers (folder 4 of 7), undated (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Africa Program Review (Dec 1970) -- Reports, Discussion Papers (folder 5 of 7) (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Africa Program Review (Dec 1970) -- Reports, Discussion Papers (folder 6 of 7), circa 1970 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Africa Program Review (Dec 1970) -- Reports, Discussion Papers (folder 7 of 7) (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Annual Reports (folder 1 of 2), 1964-1974 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Annual Reports (folder 2 of 2), 1964-1974 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Development Planning Reviews -- Tanzania and Kenya, 1970 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Middle East and Africa -- East Africa -- Report, "Administrative and Economic Program Review" by Courtney Nelson, 1977 March 4 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Middle East and Africa -- East and Central Africa -- Report, Ford Foundation in East and Central Africa, 1969 June (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Middle East and Africa -- East and Southern Africa (Nairobi) -- Report, "Fostering Progress in Africa" by Goran Hyden, 1984 October 23 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Middle East and Africa -- General -- Correspondence, Memoranda and Notes Re: Corfu Conference, Travel, etc., 1958-1984 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Middle East and Africa -- General -- Notes Re: Foundation Work in Africa, Multilateral Aid, Education, Population, Government Studies, 1961-1984 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Iran -- Report on Iran and Correspondence, 1953-1984 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Notes and Grant Information, circa 1955-1985 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Report, "Near East Program, Report and Recommendations", 1952 July (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Report, "Report of Ford Foundation Mission to Africa" by William Brown, Melvin J. Fox and John B. Howard, 1957 January 16 (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Report, Tapestry for Tomorrow: The Ford Foundation Program in the Middle East, 1964 February (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Report, The Ford Foundation in Turkey 1952-1967, 1968 (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Report, "Africa Ten Years Later" by Francis X. Sutton, 1970 December (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Report, "The Ford Foundation in the Middle East and North Africa" (folder 1 of 2), 1973 March (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Report, "The Ford Foundation in the Middle East and North Africa" (folder 2 of 2), 1973 March (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Report, "Africa and Middle East-Related Organizations in the United States Part I" by Jennifer C. Ward, 1973 August (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Middle East and Africa -- Report, Ford Foundation Assistance in North Africa, 1974 September (Box 64, Folder 5)